Fantasia 2000 is a animation, family, music film directed by James Algar.
Blending lively music and brilliant animation, this sequel to the original
'Fantasia' restores 'The Sorcerer's Apprentice' and adds seven new shorts.
Self - Introductory Host, played by Steve Martin.
Self - Host, played by Itzhak Perlman.
Self - Host, played by Quincy Jones.
Self - Host, played by Bette Midler.
Self - Host, played by James Earl Jones.
Self - Host, played by Penn Jillette.
Fantasia 2000: An Original Walt Disney Records Soundtrack is the soundtrack to
Fantasia 2000, a sequel to the animated anthology film Fantasia (1940).
It features eight individual score suites for each segment and were named after the
same title of these segments that are set to pieces of classical music.
James Levine conducted six of the tracks from the film, which are performed by the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, while the rest of the two tracks (The Sorcerer's Apperentice,
originally from the 1940 film, and Rhapsody in Blue) were originally conducted by Bruce Broughton for the film and were conducted by Levine for the soundtrack.
The album, released on November 30, 1999 by Walt Disney Records and Sony Classical Records, went on to
reach the number one spot on the Billboard Top Classical Albums chart in July 2000.
The film explores themes of magic, classical music,
orchestra, musical, live action and animation.